Stavros Niafas

Stavros Niafas received his BSc degree in Informatics Engineering from the Department of Informatics Engineering, University of Thessaly in 2014. He also holds an Msc from a postgraduate joint program of the Department of Informatics Engineering, University of West Attica and the Department of Informatics of the University of Limoges in 2016. Both his bachelor and MSc theses lied in the areas of digital image processing, computer vision and information retrieval. From October 2018 to February 2019, he worked as Artificial Intelligence Engineer in DeepMed IO - a MedTech company based in the UK which develops a system for detecting metastatic tumor regions on lymph nodes, on whole slide images. Besides the main goal, the company outsourced a side project in which he participated and involved as an AI engineer. From March till May 2019 his role changed to systems engineer.

In October 2019 he enrolled in a Msc Data Science program conducted by the NCSR Demokritos and the University of Peloponnese.

Personal Information

Place/Date of Birth **✓** sniafas@gmail.com ****+30 6945745424

Athens - 19th May 1991

% https://sniafas.github.io

Working Experience

DeepMed I/O

AI Engineer (September 2018 - February 2019)

- Participated and involved in company's outsourced project.
- Implement & improve image processing, machine & deep learning algorithms and models.
- Performance Evaluation, Metrics (AUC, Specificity, Sensitive, Accuracy).
- Produce quality plots & reports on planned meetings.

Systems Engineer (March 2019 - May 2019)

- Build, setup and maintain Deep Learning & Network Infrastructure.
- Setup endpoints for IP/IPX based LAN.
- OS and software stack setup.
- Test & deploy company's projects.
- Create technical documentation and guidelines for reference and reporting.
- Monitoring servers using BMC.
- Backup management & disaster recovery.
- Troubleshooting hardware and software problems.

Nexus Computers, nexus-service.gr

Computer Technician (April 2013 - May 2014)

- Build, repair and maintenance of computer hardware.
- Setup and configure hardware and software.
- Troubleshooting failures.
- Customer support (phone, onsite).

Skills

Computing: Python, Matlab, R, PHP, HTML/CSS, C, MySQL

Tools & Technologies: Numpy, Pandas, Scikit-Learn, Docker, Keras, Tensorflow, OpenCV,

Jupyter, Git, Scrum, Google Cloud Platform, LATEX Operating Systems: Linux (Debian based), Windows

Office Applications: LibreOffice, MS-Office

Soft Skills: Team-working, Self Motivated, Patience, Flexibility, Active Listening, Ownership

Knowledge Sharing

Education

NCSR Demokritos - University of Peloponnese

MSc in Data Science, 2019-2020

TEI of Athens - Université de Limoges

MSc. Informatics Engineer, 2016

Informatics, Image synthesis & Graphics Design Internet & Multimedia Technology, GPA: 13.96/20

Thesis Title: Image Retrieval platform for building recognition in urban environments

Supervisor: Professor Anastasios Kesidis

TEI of Central Greece

BSc. Informatics Engineer, 2014

School of Technological Applications, GPA:7.33

Thesis Title: Evaluation and development of Feature Extraction Methods in WCE Video

Supervisor: Dr. Evaggelos Spyrou

Seminars

Summer school of National Centre for Scientific Research "Demokritos", 2014

Units of Excellence $E\Lambda/\Lambda AK$, http://eellak.gr

Educational Circle: IoT

(Internet Of Things) with Arduino II – event driven programming

Backend-logic Team **Q**Github Repo

Units of Excellence $E\Lambda/\Lambda AK$

Summer School Programming Arduino controlling Diviot-car Project & Development of web interface for event-driven programming

Github Repo

Units of Excellence $E\Lambda/\Lambda AK$

Summer School: Development of a wearable arduino lillypad based system for sport activities.

ComputerVision team

OGithub Repo

Awards and Fellowships

FOSDEM 2017, Brussels

Granted Visitor with team $E\Lambda/\Lambda AK$

Event organised by volunteers to promote the widespread use of free

and open source software

Units of Excellence FOSS Awards

Educational Circle: Internet of Things
Money award for best contributed project.

Languages

English: English Speaking Board (C2)

German: Goethe Institut Athen - Zertifikat Deutsch (B1)

Journals

E. Spyrou, D. Iakovidis, S. Niafas and A. Koulaouzidis

Comparative Assessment of Feature Extraction Methods for Visual Odometry in Wireless

Capsule Endoscopy

Computers in Biology and Medicine, Elsevier, **DOI**

Conferences

E. Mitsianis, E. Spyrou, T. Giannakopoulos, S. Niafas and S. Perantonis

Deep learned features for image retrieval.

In Proc. of Hellenic Conference on Artificial Intelligence (SETN), 2018